Michael F. Zhang

3725 Armour Court, Woodridge, IL 60517 Phone: 630.486.6411 Email: mfzhang2@illinois.edu

Objective

Accumulate and acquire knowledge in the field of Physics.

Professional Statement

Responsible and motivated young adult with high school diploma in pursuit of a bachelor's degree in Physics. Great with analysis and problem solving as well as communication. Experienced in teaching, explaining, and leading. Well-versed in Mathematics, Physics, and writing.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (2017-present) — Champaign, IL Expected Graduation Date: May 2021 Major: Physics

Experience

2pvv	
Service Desk Analyst Intern at MultiPlan Inc. June 2017 - August 2017	 Handled and processed tickets initiated by healthcare professionals and their respective clients. Completed a project that enabled MultiPlan to comply with mandatory regulations. Presented to the CIO, CTO, and various managers in the Information Technology department.
First Class Leader at Naperville North High School August 2015 - May 2017	 Led students through interactive activities. Educated peers about issues faced by students such as drug abuse, mental illness, and bullying. Provided support and help for those facing such issues.
Vice President of Badminton Club during High School August 2016 - May 2017	 Act as stand-in for president when absent. Disseminate information regarding scheduling and promotion. Act as overseer for badminton activities. Set up equipment.
Humanities Capstone Essay and Presentation Development August 2016 - December 2016	 Involved in an independent study with a supervising mentor in an established school setting. Independently wrote a treatise on philosophical ideas involving humility and introspection. Presented essay to a group of peers.
Internship at APS at Argonne National Laboratory July 2016 - August 2016	 Developed a Python program currently being used by beamline scientists. Collaborated with the High Pressure Collaborative Access Team to upgrade software. Attended meetings involving scientific discussions.
Peer Tutor at Naperville North High School August 2015 - May 2016	 Tutored peers one-on-one in various subjects before school in an established school program. Assisted peers in developing critical thinking skills. Overcame challenges as a group in solving problems.
Science Olympiad Varsity Competitor January 2016 - May 2016	 Self studied topics not included in the standard high school and AP curriculum with my partner. Used computer software to create a simulated protein model and a physical protein model. Competed against various schools in Dupage County in different events.

Achievements

Selected as a recipient of the 2017-18 MultiPlan Scholarship award
Selected to receive the 2017 Village of Woodridge/ProLogis Foundation Scholarship Award
National Merit Commended Student
AP Scholar with Distinction
Science Olympiad Varsity Chemistry Lab Event 3rd place medalist

Skills

Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel Java, Python English (fluent), Chinese (Intermediate)